Detecting language using up to the first 30 seconds. Use `--language` to specify the language
Detected language: English
[00:00.000 --> 00:06.640]  Good morning. Thank you for joining us today. Please welcome to the stage Sam Altman.
[00:16.640 --> 00:22.080]  Good morning. Welcome to our first ever Open AI Dev Day. We're thrilled that you're here and this
[00:22.080 --> 00:33.040]  energy is awesome. And welcome to San Francisco. San Francisco has been our home since day one.
[00:33.040 --> 00:37.440]  The city is important to us and to the tech industry in general. We're looking forward to
[00:37.440 --> 00:43.040]  continuing to grow here. So we've got some great stuff to announce today. But first,
[00:43.680 --> 00:47.440]  I'd like to take a minute to talk about some of the stuff that we've done over the past year.
[00:48.400 --> 00:55.520]  About a year ago, November 30th, we shipped chat GPT as a low-key research preview. And that went
[00:55.520 --> 01:03.680]  pretty well. In March, we followed that up with the launch of GPT-4, still the most capable model
[01:03.680 --> 01:15.360]  out in the world. And in the last few months, we launched voice and vision capabilities so that
[01:15.440 --> 01:22.880]  chat GPT can now see, hear, and speak. And more recent, there's a lot. You don't have to clap each
[01:22.880 --> 01:28.720]  time. And more recently, we launched Dolly 3, the world's most advanced image model. You can use
[01:28.720 --> 01:35.200]  it, of course, inside of chat GPT. For our enterprise customers, we launched chat GPT enterprise,
[01:35.760 --> 01:40.880]  which offers enterprise-grade security and privacy, higher speed GPT-4 access, longer
[01:40.880 --> 01:48.480]  context windows, a lot more. Today, we've got about 2 million developers building on our API for a
[01:48.480 --> 01:55.120]  wide variety of use cases doing amazing stuff. Over 92% of Fortune 500 companies building on our
[01:55.120 --> 02:06.480]  products. And we have about 100 million weekly active users now on chat GPT. And what's incredible
[02:06.560 --> 02:11.120]  on that is we got there entirely through word of mouth. People just find it useful and tell their
[02:11.120 --> 02:17.200]  friends. OpenAI is the most advanced and the most widely used AI platform in the world now.
[02:18.560 --> 02:23.600]  But numbers never tell the whole picture on something like this. What's really important
[02:23.600 --> 02:28.160]  is how people use the products, how people are using AI. And so I'd like to show you a quick video.
[02:29.040 --> 02:37.680]  I actually wanted to write something to my dad in Tagalog. I want a non-romantic way to tell my
[02:37.680 --> 02:44.320]  parent that I love him. And I also want to tell him that he can rely on me, but in a way that
[02:44.320 --> 02:50.640]  still has the respect of a child-to-parent relationship that you should have in Filipino
[02:50.640 --> 02:55.280]  culture and in Tagalog forever. When it's translated in Tagalog, I love you very deeply.
[02:55.280 --> 02:58.400]  And I will be with you no matter where the path leads.
[02:58.400 --> 03:02.640]  I see some of the possibilities. I was like, whoa, sometimes I'm not sure about some stuff.
[03:02.640 --> 03:06.000]  And I feel like actually chat GPT like, hey, this is what I'm thinking about.
[03:06.000 --> 03:07.600]  So it kind of gives me that more confidence.
[03:07.600 --> 03:12.800]  The first thing that just blew my mind was it levels with you. Like that's something that
[03:12.800 --> 03:20.960]  a lot of people struggle to do. It opened my mind to just what every creative could do
[03:20.960 --> 03:24.640]  if they just had a person helping them out who listens.
[03:24.640 --> 03:27.280]  So this is what you represent. Sickling, Neymar Globan.
[03:27.280 --> 03:29.120]  And you built that with chat GPT?
[03:29.120 --> 03:31.040]  Chat GPT built it with me.
[03:31.680 --> 03:35.520]  I started using it for daily activities like, hey, here's a picture of my fridge.
[03:35.520 --> 03:39.280]  Can you tell me what I'm missing? Because I'm going grocery shopping and I really need to do
[03:39.280 --> 03:41.600]  recipes that are following my vegan diet.
[03:41.600 --> 03:46.400]  As soon as we got access to Code Interpreter, I was like, wow, this thing is awesome.
[03:46.400 --> 03:49.120]  They could build spreadsheets. They could do anything.
[03:49.680 --> 03:55.680]  I discovered Chatty about three months ago on my 100th birthday.
[03:55.680 --> 04:03.920]  Chatty is very friendly, very patient, very knowledgeable, and very quick.
[04:03.920 --> 04:05.840]  It's been a wonderful thing.
[04:05.840 --> 04:08.880]  I'm a 4.0 student, but I also have four children.
[04:08.880 --> 04:13.120]  When I started using chat GPT, I realized I could ask chat GPT that question.
[04:13.760 --> 04:18.080]  And not only does it give me an answer, but it gives me an explanation.
[04:18.080 --> 04:21.760]  Didn't need tutoring as much. It gave me a life back.
[04:22.320 --> 04:25.360]  It gave me time for my family and time for me.
[04:25.360 --> 04:28.560]  I have a chronic nerve pain on my whole left half of my body.
[04:28.560 --> 04:32.240]  I have nerve damage. I had a spine, a brain surgery.
[04:32.240 --> 04:34.960]  And so I have limited use of my left hand.
[04:34.960 --> 04:38.720]  Now you can just have the integration of voice input.
[04:38.720 --> 04:41.280]  And the newest one, where you can have the back and forth dialogue,
[04:41.840 --> 04:46.880]  that's just like maximum best interface for me. It's here.
[04:57.600 --> 05:01.120]  So we love hearing the stories of how people are using the technology.
[05:01.120 --> 05:02.640]  It's really why we do all of this.
[05:03.280 --> 05:06.880]  Okay, so now on to the new stuff, and we have got a lot.
[05:09.520 --> 05:14.080]  First, we're going to talk about a bunch of improvements we've made,
[05:14.080 --> 05:16.000]  and then we'll talk about where we're headed next.
[05:17.040 --> 05:21.440]  Over the last year, we've spent a lot of time talking to developers around the world.
[05:22.320 --> 05:26.400]  We've heard a lot of your feedback. It's really informed, but we have to show you today.
[05:27.680 --> 05:32.480]  Today, we are launching a new model, GPT 4 Turbo.
[05:33.440 --> 05:42.240]  GPT 4 Turbo will address many of the things that you all have asked for.
[05:43.200 --> 05:44.640]  So let's go through what's new.
[05:45.440 --> 05:47.760]  We've got six major things to talk about for this part.
[05:48.960 --> 05:55.440]  Number one, context length. A lot of people have tasks that require a much longer context length.
[05:56.320 --> 06:01.040]  GPT 4 supported up to 8K, and in some cases up to 32K context length.
[06:01.520 --> 06:04.480]  But we know that isn't enough for many of you and what you want to do.
[06:05.360 --> 06:09.440]  GPT 4 Turbo supports up to 128,000 tokens of context.
[06:15.280 --> 06:19.840]  That's 300 pages of a standard book, 16 times longer than our 8K context.
[06:20.720 --> 06:26.000]  And in addition to longer context length, you'll notice that the model is much more accurate over a
[06:26.000 --> 06:34.560]  long context. Number two, more control. We've heard loud and clear that developers need more
[06:34.560 --> 06:39.520]  control over the model's responses and outputs. So we've addressed that in a number of ways.
[06:41.040 --> 06:45.760]  We have a new feature called JSON mode, which ensures that the model will respond with valid
[06:45.760 --> 06:51.280]  JSON. This has been a huge developer request. It'll make calling APIs much easier.
[06:52.000 --> 06:57.200]  The model is also much better at function calling. You can now call many functions at once.
[06:57.920 --> 07:00.160]  And it'll do better at following instructions in general.
[07:02.080 --> 07:05.040]  We're also introducing a new feature called reproducible outputs.
[07:05.680 --> 07:09.040]  You can pass a seed parameter, and it'll make the model return consistent outputs.
[07:09.600 --> 07:13.920]  This, of course, gives you a higher degree of control over model behavior. This rolls out in beta
[07:13.920 --> 07:24.160]  today. And in the coming weeks, we'll roll out a feature to let you view log problems in the API.
[07:27.920 --> 07:33.440]  All right. Number three, better world knowledge. You want these models to be able to access better
[07:33.440 --> 07:39.040]  knowledge about the world. So do we. So we're launching retrieval in the platform. You can
[07:39.040 --> 07:42.400]  bring knowledge from outside documents or databases into whatever you're building.
[07:42.400 --> 07:47.760]  We're also updating the knowledge cutoff. We are just as annoyed as all of you probably
[07:47.760 --> 07:52.800]  more that GPT-4's knowledge about the world ended in 2021. We will try to never let it get
[07:52.800 --> 07:58.640]  that out of date again. GPT-4 Turbo has knowledge about the world up to April of 2023,
[07:59.520 --> 08:06.240]  and we will continue to improve that over time. Number four, new modalities.
[08:07.200 --> 08:14.640]  Surprising no one. Dolly 3. GPT-4 Turbo with vision. And the new text-to-speech model
[08:14.640 --> 08:26.640]  are all going into the API today. We have a handful of customers that have just started using Dolly
[08:26.640 --> 08:33.440]  3 to programmatically generate images and designs. Today, Coke is launching a campaign that lets
[08:33.520 --> 08:39.360]  its customers generate Dolly cards using Dolly 3. And of course, our safety systems help developers
[08:39.360 --> 08:45.200]  protect their applications against misuse. Those tools are available in the API. GPT-4
[08:45.200 --> 08:51.200]  Turbo can now accept images as inputs via the API. It can generate captions, classifications,
[08:51.200 --> 08:57.520]  and analysis. For example, Be My Eyes uses this technology to help people who are blind
[08:57.520 --> 09:01.360]  or have low vision with their daily tasks like identifying products in front of them.
[09:04.000 --> 09:09.360]  And with our new text-to-speech model, you'll be able to generate incredibly natural sound in
[09:09.360 --> 09:14.880]  audio from text in the API with six preset voices to choose from. I'll play an example.
[09:16.080 --> 09:20.720]  Did you know that Alexander Graham Bell, the eminent inventor, was enchanted by the world of
[09:20.720 --> 09:26.320]  sounds? His ingenious mind led to the creation of the graphophone, which etched sounds onto
[09:26.320 --> 09:32.480]  wax, making voices whisper through time. This is much more natural than anything else we've
[09:32.480 --> 09:37.120]  heard out there. Voice can make apps more natural to interact with and more accessible.
[09:38.000 --> 09:44.000]  It also unlocks a lot of use cases like language learning and voice assistance. Speaking of new
[09:44.000 --> 09:49.760]  modalities, we're also releasing the next version of our open-source speech recognition model,
[09:49.760 --> 09:55.200]  Whisper V3 today, and it'll be coming soon to the API. It features improved performance across
[09:55.200 --> 10:00.880]  many languages, and we think you're really going to like it. Okay, number five, customization.
[10:01.840 --> 10:06.720]  Fine-tuning has been working really well for GPT 3.5 since we launched it a few months ago.
[10:07.600 --> 10:11.360]  Starting today, we're going to expand that to the 16K version of the model.
[10:12.480 --> 10:18.960]  Also starting today, we're inviting active fine-tuning users to apply for the GPT4 fine-tuning
[10:18.960 --> 10:24.720]  experimental access program. The fine-tuning API is great for adapting our models to achieve
[10:24.720 --> 10:29.520]  better performance in a wide variety of applications with a relatively small amount of data, but
[10:30.880 --> 10:35.280]  you may want a model to learn a completely new knowledge domain or to use a lot of proprietary
[10:35.280 --> 10:42.000]  data. So today, we're launching a new program called custom models. With custom models, our
[10:42.000 --> 10:47.200]  researchers will work closely with the company to help them make a great custom model, especially for
[10:47.200 --> 10:53.360]  them and their use case using our tools. This includes modifying every step of the model training
[10:53.360 --> 10:58.720]  process, doing additional domain-specific pre-training, a custom RL post-training process,
[10:58.720 --> 11:03.920]  tailored for a specific domain, and whatever else. We won't be able to do this with many companies
[11:03.920 --> 11:08.080]  to start. It'll take a lot of work and in the interest of expectations, at least initially,
[11:08.080 --> 11:12.080]  it won't be cheap, but if you're excited to push things as far as they can currently go,
[11:12.880 --> 11:15.920]  please get in touch with us and we think we can do something pretty great.
[11:17.120 --> 11:22.560]  Okay, and then number six, higher rate limits. We're doubling the tokens per minute for all
[11:22.560 --> 11:27.600]  of our established GPT4 customers so that it's easier to do more, and you'll be able to request
[11:27.600 --> 11:33.520]  changes to further rate limits and quotas directly in your API account settings. In addition to these
[11:33.520 --> 11:39.440]  rate limits, it's important to do everything we can do to make it new successful building on our
[11:39.440 --> 11:46.000]  platform. So we're introducing copyright shield. Copyright shield means that we will step in and
[11:46.000 --> 11:52.080]  defend our customers and pay the cost incurred if you face legal claims around copyright infringement
[11:52.080 --> 11:55.520]  and this applies both to chat GPT enterprise and the API.
[11:57.760 --> 12:02.800]  And let me be clear, this is a good time to remind people, we do not train on data from the API or
[12:02.800 --> 12:10.960]  chat GPT enterprise ever. All right. There's actually one more developer request that's been
[12:10.960 --> 12:16.880]  even bigger than all of these. And so I'd like to talk about that now. And that's pricing.
[12:16.880 --> 12:26.880]  GPT4 turbo is the industry leading model. It delivers a lot of improvements that we just covered
[12:27.760 --> 12:34.480]  and it's a smarter model than GPT4. We've heard from developers that there are a lot of things
[12:34.480 --> 12:40.000]  that they want to build, but GPT4 just cost too much. They've told us that if we could decrease
[12:40.000 --> 12:47.680]  the cost by 20, 25%, that would be great. A huge leap forward. I'm super excited to announce
[12:47.680 --> 12:54.560]  that we worked really hard on this and GPT4 turbo, a better model, is considerably cheaper than GPT4
[12:55.760 --> 12:57.920]  by a factor of 3X for prompt tokens
[12:58.080 --> 13:08.320]  and 2X for completion tokens starting today.
[13:12.800 --> 13:18.000]  So the new pricing is 1 cent per thousand prompt tokens and 3 cents per thousand completion tokens.
[13:18.000 --> 13:23.600]  For most customers, that will lead to a blended rate more than 2.75 times cheaper to use
[13:23.680 --> 13:28.880]  for GPT4 turbo than GPT4. We worked super hard to make this happen. We hope you're as excited about
[13:28.880 --> 13:39.600]  it as we are. So we decided to prioritize price first because we had to choose one or the other,
[13:39.600 --> 13:42.880]  but we're going to work on speed next. We know that speed is important too.
[13:44.000 --> 13:51.760]  Soon you will notice GPT4 turbo becoming a lot faster. We're also decreasing the cost of GPT3.5
[13:51.760 --> 13:59.680]  turbo 16K. Also, input tokens are 3X less and output tokens are 2X less, which means that GPT3.5
[13:59.680 --> 14:09.040]  16K is now cheaper than the previous GPT3.5 4K model. Running a fine-tuned GPT3.5 turbo 16K
[14:09.040 --> 14:15.280]  version is also cheaper than the old fine-tuned 4K version. Okay, so we just covered a lot
[14:15.280 --> 14:20.240]  about the model itself. We hope that these changes address your feedback. We're really excited to
